<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joey Lynch&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://jolynch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joey Lynch&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:22:58 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jolynch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Joey Lynch. I mostly hack on open source distributed systems problems, but also enjoy economics, politics, and debate.
I should have more info up soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>Below are a collection of conference talks or other presentations that I&amp;rsquo;ve given, typically related to distributed systems or other software engineering topics:
 Iterating on Stateful Services in the Cloud (2018): A talk at re:Invent 2018 about how Netflix manages stateful services (such as datastores or databases) in the AWS cloud. Contains a lot of concrete advice for managing state in AWS. Repair Service and Cassandra (2018): Part of Netflix&amp;rsquo;s OSS Meetup about Polyglot Persistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Below are some of my projects roughly categorized by area.
Distributed Systems  synapse and nerve service mesh aka SmartStack. I help maintain and have contributed significant features to Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s service mesh, including improving the scalability of the system by multiple orders of magnitude (Yelp ran tens of thousands of containers across a global network with full global service discovery), and extending Synapse to be fully pluggable and support any proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose of this Blog</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/purpose_of_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 11:30:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/purpose_of_blog/</guid>
      <description>I figured it was time to start a proper personal/tech blog given how much I enjoy writing about the crazy fun and wierd distributed systems problems that I work on.
Initially I am planning on writing up my current rants on high performance software systems as understood through food service analogies, but I imagine it&amp;rsquo;ll evolve from there to just talking about cool systems problems I work on every day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>