<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tags on Joey Lynch&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://jolynch.github.io/tags/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tags on Joey Lynch&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 12:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://jolynch.github.io/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Speed up the DMV</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/how_to_speed_up_the_dmv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/how_to_speed_up_the_dmv/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to apply some of the lessons learned from the &amp;ldquo;distributed systems as food service analogies&amp;rdquo; to something unrelated to food but that does devour Americans&amp;rsquo; souls: the Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV).
The DMV is where happy Americans go to wait, sometimes for many moons, just to be told that they have the wrong identifying documents for a driver&amp;rsquo;s license renewal. It is an unfortunately dreadful introduction to government bureaucracy, and is a uniform topic of derision for newly driving teenagers (and indeed adults) across the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domino&#39;s Is A Pretty Good Content Delivery Network For Pizza</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/dominos_is_a_good_cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/dominos_is_a_good_cdn/</guid>
      <description>Today on the &amp;ldquo;distributed systems as food service analogy&amp;rdquo; series we visit low latency pizza delivery and how they relate to Content Delivery Networks (CDN).
Like with Jimmy John&amp;rsquo;s, I often order Domino&amp;rsquo;s pizza not because it tastes particularly good but because Domino&amp;rsquo;s is efficient! They are one of the only pizza places I know that offer a latency service level objective (SLO) of less than thirty minutes. To achieve this promise, they use a number of common techniques used by Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) to ensure that web content such as photos, code and even videos get to your browser or device quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy John&#39;s is like a High-Performance Web Service</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/jimmy_johns_and_web_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/jimmy_johns_and_web_services/</guid>
      <description>Today on the &amp;ldquo;distributed systems as food service analogy&amp;rdquo; series we visit one of my favorites: sandwich shops.
Most sandwich places are absolutely terrible at efficiently processing my sandwich order. They have limited workers that constantly context switch and are entirely unable to pipeline (looking at you Subway). Jimmy John&amp;rsquo;s, however, is wonderfully efficient and a model for all other sandwich places.
In this post, I will explore how Jimmy John&amp;rsquo;s operates as a high-performance web (micro)service might.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermarkets And Efficient Queueing: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/supermarkets_and_efficient_queueing_part_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/supermarkets_and_efficient_queueing_part_2/</guid>
      <description>This post wraps up the two part writeup on queueing theory and understanding computer systems using supermarkets within the larger &amp;ldquo;distributed systems as food service analogy&amp;rdquo; series.
 Part 1: Basics of queueing theory and minimizing latency. Part 2: More advanced techniques past optimizing latency.  We learned in Part 1 that we should keep our queues together and if we must form separate queues we should always try to pick the shortest queue if we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermarkets And Efficient Queueing: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/supermarkets_and_efficient_queueing_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/supermarkets_and_efficient_queueing_part_1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to kick off the &amp;ldquo;distributed systems as food service analogy&amp;rdquo; series with the basics. In this two part post I cover the basics of queueing theory, and how we can understand it with the help of your every day supermarket or grocery store.
 Part 1: Basics of queueing theory and minimizing latency. Part 2: More advanced techniques past optimizing latency.  Why should software engineers care about Queueing Theory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose of this Blog</title>
      <link>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/purpose_of_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 11:30:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jolynch.github.io/posts/purpose_of_blog/</guid>
      <description>I figured it was time to start a proper personal/tech blog given how much I enjoy writing about the crazy fun and wierd distributed systems problems that I work on.
Initially I am planning on writing up my current rants on high performance software systems as understood through food service analogies, but I imagine it&amp;rsquo;ll evolve from there to just talking about cool systems problems I work on every day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
